本:嘀哒嘀哒嘀哒嘀哒.60分钟.
Ben: Tick tick tick tick.Hi this is sixty minutes.But it won't take that long.
用不了那么长时间的.嗨,
Hi, I'm Ben seaver, and welcome to my class project.
我是本*希佛,欢迎你到我的班级作业,
A day in the life of the Seavers.And what a day it is.
.那,
It's chore day and everybody has a job to do.Mrs.
它是怎样的一天呢?这是家务繁忙的一天,
Seaver and Carol are going to clean the drapes,
所有人都没有闲着.
and Doctor seaver's using carol's computor to write some article for some
希佛太太和开萝尔准备清洗窗帘,而希佛医生正在用开萝尔的计算机为精神病学杂志撰写文章.
mental magazine.Oh yeah, he's a psychiatrist.
哦,他可是一个精神病科的专家.
And Mike's gotta paint his room, or dads gonna know the reason why.
迈克想要粉刷自己的房间.而我呢,
I don't even care what grade I get on this.
正想为您做件好事,卡特尔太太.
I just want to do A good job for you Mrs.Cutter.
杰妮:本,当时你应该提醒我的.
Jenny: Ben, you were supposed to mention me.
本:好好,杰妮*福斯特,
Ben: Ok, ok.Jenny Foster, another one of your fine students,
你的另外一个好心的同学正在帮我照看录相机呢.
is helping me by running the video camera.
杰妮:嗨,卡特尔太太.
Jenny: Hi Mrs.Cutter.
本:有一件事您……有一件事,和希佛家有关的,
Ben: Well, one thing you're...
您注意到没有,那就是我们一家人相处地十分融洽.
one thing you are going to notice about the Seavers, is how well we get along.
麦琪:好了,杰森……
Maggie: Come on Jason:..
杰森:麦琪,勤俭节约和抠门两者之间是有区别的.
Jason: Maggie, threes a difference between frugal and cheap.
麦琪:好了,我把话收回.你这不是抠门,是节约.
Maggie: Ok, I take it back.You're a frugal-skate.
杰森:用一位可靠,又不贵的老维修工,
Jason: Well, I don't see what's wrong with going with the old, reliable,
有什么不对么?我们已经用他几年了.
inexpensive handy man we've always used for years.
麦琪:亲爱的,火炉可不是一扇破了的屏风门,
Maggie: Honey, a furnace is not a broken screen door.
其中的机械构造非常复杂.
It's a complicated piece of machinery.
杰森:我觉得吉米能搞定这件事情.而且,我有提到他收费便宜了么?
Jason: Well, I think Jimmy can handle it.And did I mention he works cheap?
麦琪:那你会雇他进行心肝手术么?
Maggie: Would you hire him to perform open heart surgery?
麦琪:那我会也找他给我做一个估测.
Jason: Well I'd let him give me an estimate.
麦琪:本,杰妮,现在不行,求你了.
Maggie: Ben, Jenny, not now, please.
本:继续,会很棒.
Ben: Keep rolling, this could be good.
麦琪:亲爱的,我也很喜欢杰姆这人,
Maggie: Honey, you know I love dear sweet Jimmy as much as you and the
跟你一样,孩子们也喜欢.
kids do.
杰森:当然了.那为什么要挫伤他的自尊心?
Jason: Of course.So why not destroy the man's dignity?
麦琪:哈!
Maggie: Ha!
麦琪:看起来他俩像是在争论,其实不是的,
Ben: It may look like they're arguing, but they are not.
他们管这个叫讨论.
They call this discussing.
麦琪:本,我告诉过你了,关掉.
Maggie: Ben, I told you to turn that off.
杰森:不,继续拍,本.可能会很不错.
Jason: No, keep rolling Ben.This could be great stuff.
麦琪:本,我不会再提醒你第二遍.
Maggie: Ben I am not going to ask you again.
本:觉得好像有人请我参加这个讨论了.
Ben: Uh oh!It looks like I have been invited to participate in this discussion.
(门铃)
(door bell)
本:开始拍,继续.
Ben: Start rolling.Come on.
迈克:我知道了,我知道了.
Mike: I got it, I got it, I got it!
鲍纳我告诉过你不要电话……哟,吉母!
Boner I told you not to ring...Yo Jimmy!
吉米:迈克!
Jimmy: Yo Mike!
迈克:(犹豫)
Mike: Ehh.
吉米:让我看看.
Jimmy: Alright, let me see it.
迈克:哦,好的.
Mike: Oh right.
吉米:还可以.现在,用力给我夯,就这儿.
Jimmy: Not bad.Now give me your best punch, right here.
迈克:不,不,我不行.
Mike: No, no I can't.
吉米:来呀.
Jimmy: Come on.
迈克:不,真的不行.
Mike: No really.I can't.
吉米:胆小鬼!
Jimmy: Wimp!
迈克:嗨,来吧,吉米.
Mike: Hey come on Jimmy.
吉米:歪种!来吧,(迈克 击中他)哦!
Jimmy: Weenie!Come on.(mike punches him) Ohh!
迈克:吉米,对不起.你没事吧?很对不起.
Mike: Jimmy I'm sorry.Are you ok?Look, I'm sorry.
吉米:没事.我一点儿事没有,从来没有这么好的.
Jimmy: It's alright.I'm perfectly alright.Never been better.
麦琪:吉米!
Maggie: Jimmy!
吉米:希佛太太,和以前一样漂亮.
Jimmy: Mrs.Weaver.Pretty as ever.
麦琪:你没事吧?
Maggie: Are you alright?
吉米:没事,我很好.
Jimmy: Yes, I'm I'm great.Oh!Just a minute.
哦!等等,那个漂亮的年轻人不会是……
That pretty young there couldn't be...
开萝尔:对喽,就是我啊.
Carol: Yep, it's me.
吉米:卡瑞尔.
Jimmy: Karen.
开萝尔:不对,是开萝尔.
Carol: Carol.
杰森:吉米,你小子.你好啊?
Jason: Jimmy you son of a gun.
吉米:哦,我最喜欢的大夫,你还好么?
Jimmy: Oh, how's my favourite medicine man?
杰森:我最喜欢的维修工,你还好么?
Jason: How's my favourite handy man?
吉米:哦,我一直在想你们,很高兴你刚才叫我.
Jimmy: Oh, I've been missing you folks.I'm glad you called me.
杰森: 那是麦琪的主意,她坚持要你来.
Jason: Well it was Maggie's idea.She insisted.
吉米:我听说了,你的火炉有点毛病?
Jimmy: Well, I understand you have a sick furnace?
杰森:它打得着火,但总是中途熄火.
Jason: Well it goes on but it won't stay on.
吉米:哦哦哦,让我看一看.
Jimmy: Oh oh oh, well, let me take a look.
麦琪:吉米,火炉在地下室,应该那边走.
Maggie: Jimmy, the furnace is in the basement.That way.
吉米:对,不过我的工具在我的车里,那边?
Jimmy: Yes, but me tools is in me truck.That way.
麦琪:哦,没错.
Maggie: Oh, right.
本:火炉可能会是今天希佛家最大的新闻.卡特尔太太,
Ben: It looks like the furnace could be the big story today at the Seavers.
您完全可以放心,我会赶到那儿的.
And of course Mrs.Cutter, you can count on me to be there.
麦琪:他抖得多厉害啊,你看到了没有?
Maggie: Did you see how shaky he was?
杰森:没有.
Jason: No.
麦琪:我走进房间的时候,
Maggie: When I walked in the room he was wheezing,
他还正在喘粗气.
he couldn't catch his breath.
迈克:哦,那是因为打了他一拳,击中了他的胃.
Mike: Oh that's cos I punched him in the stomach.
麦琪:哦,好啊!你们男人都一个鼻孔出气的.
Maggie: Oh fine!You men just stick together.
杰森:你不是还要粉刷你的卧室么?
Jason: I believe you have a bedroom to paint.
迈克:嗨,我早就干到你前面去了,爸爸.
Mike: Hey, I'm well ahead of you dad.
杰森:好了,你知道规矩的.完工之前,任何人不能过来.
Jason: Ok, you know the rules.Nobody comes over until it's done.
迈克:嗨,你挺了解我啊.
Mike: Hey, you know me.
杰森:当然了.除此之外,
Jason: Yes I sure do.
我希望,那间卧室在今晚之前时分粉刷完毕.
And in spite of that, I still expect that room painted buy tonight.
迈克:没问题.
Mike: No problem.You got it.
鲍纳:迈克!
Boner: Mikey!
迈克:嗨,鲍纳.
Mike: Hey Boner.
鲍纳:那大惊喜是什么?
Boner: So what's the big surprise?
迈克:上楼我再告诉你,行么?
Mike: I'll tell you upstairs.ok.
鲍纳:很棒,是不是?
Boner: Something great aint it?
迈克:鲍纳,你什么都不知道.
Mike: Bone, you have no idea.
鲍纳:我从来都没知道过.
Boner: I never do.
杰森:不有担心,他过一会儿就下来.
Jason: Don't worry.He'll be down in a second.
哦,你觉得他年老体衰,是不是?
Oh, you think he's too old, don't you?
得了,直说吧.
Come on, just say it.
麦琪:亲爱的,有一些人他就是不知道什么时候应该收手,
Maggie: Honey, some people just don't know when to hang it up.
比如,穆罕默德*阿里.
Like Mohammed Ali.
杰森:你说什么?
Jason: Pardon me.
麦琪:多年以来,他是最伟大的,
Maggie: Well for years he was the greatest,
可是现在呢,他还能么?
and now he's killing roaches on TV.
这是我在咖啡厅里听到一些体育记者说的.
I overheard some sports reporters in the cafeteria.
杰森:哦!
Jason: Oh!
麦琪:亲爱的,吉米肯定有过那种时候,
Maggie: Honey, there was a day when Jimmy could handle something as
他可以修好像火炉这么复杂的物件,但是现在我担心他不行了.
complicated as a furnace, but now I'm afraid he's lost his fast ball.
杰森:你跟那帮体育记者呆了多久?
Jason: How much time do you spend with these sports guys?
吉米:好咧,开始干活.时间就是金钱,我的时间,
Jimmy: Ok, let's get this show on the road.Time is money.My time, your money.
你的金钱.哦,好像是刻不容缓.
Oh, sounds like there is not a moment to lose.
杰森:你知道它是怎么回事么?
Jason: You know what it is?
吉米:那肯定.你们一直在用这个洗衣机似的东西给房子加热.开个玩笑.
Jimmy: Sure.You've been trying to heat the house with the washing machine.
一个小小修理工的幽默.你好啊,啊!
It's a joke.A little handy man humour.Hello, Ah ah, yeah!Sticky solenoids.
粘乎乎的线圈,加点润滑油,她就会好的.
A little lubrication and she'll be fine.
杰森:太好了.好了,麦琪.
Jason: Perfect.Right Maggie.
麦琪:谢谢你,吉米.
Maggie: Yeah.Thank you Jimmy.
吉米:我会把帐单给您送过来的.
Jimmy: I'll send you a bill.
杰森:吉米,火炉怎么样了?
Jason: Jimmy, what about the furnace?
吉米:哦,那个也有毛病么?
Jimmy: Oh, we having trouble with that too are you?
迈克:它的美丽之处是,
Mike: And you know, the beauty of it is Bone,
鲍纳,粉刷墙壁是发达你的胸肌的最好方法,
there's nothing better than painting for building up your chest.
这方法坦率的讲你可以用.
Which frankly you could use.
鲍纳:你真的这么认为么?
Boner: You really think so?
迈克:当然.你知道么,阿诺德*施瓦辛格原来就是一个油漆工.
Mike: Yeah sure.And did you know that Arnold Schwarzenegger started out as a painter
鲍纳:知道!
Boner: Yeah!
迈克:真的么? 我正用我一生的时间在这儿,鲍纳.
Mike: You did?Well I'm having the time of my life over here Bone.
鲍纳:看起来挺有趣.
Boner: It looks like fun.
迈克:如果你以为我会让你干,那你现在就可以走了,
Mike: And if you think I'm going to let you do any part of it,
好么?
you might as well just split right now.OK?
鲍纳:真的么?
Boner: Really?
迈克:对,即使你跪下来求我,我也不会让给你干的.
Mike: Yeah, not even if you got down on your knees and begged me to.
鲍纳:那是对待自己朋友的方式么?
Boner: Is that a way to treat you buddy?
迈克:哦,你说的对,兄弟.来,你试一试.
Mike: Oh, you know.You're right buddy.Here, you give it a shot.
鲍纳:太好了.不,我不行,我干不了.
Boner: Great.No, I can't.I can't do it.
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
鲍纳:因为我知道了它对于你来说是如此的重要,所以我不能这么做.
Boner: I can't do it knowing how much it means to you mike.
迈克:鲍纳,出去,赶紧走吧.听明白了么!走,我这儿还有事做呢.
Mike: Boner, get out , just go.Alright!Leave, I've got stuff to do here.
鲍纳:迈克,你真的愿意让我替你粉刷你的卧室么?
Boner: Mike, do you want me to paint your room for you?
迈克:对,我愿意.
Mike: Yes I do.
鲍纳:那你为什么不开门见山就这么说呢?
Boner: Then why didn't you just ask in the first place?
迈克:因为,鲍纳,我觉得没有谁会那么上钩.
Mike: Because, Boner, I didn't think anyone was that gullible.
鲍纳:好了,下一次,装的再像些.
Boner: Well next time, give me some credit.Hu.
杰森:可是,幽闭恐怖症可能会有另外一种功能紊乱的症状,
Jason: But, Claustrophobia can be a symptom of another disorder that ..
它……不需要你说任何事,而我可以读懂你的心思.好了,
needs you don't have to say a thing, I can read your mind.
如果他忘记了他之所以在地下室的原因,那会怎么样?他确实把洗衣机给修好了.
Alright, so what if he forgot why he was in the basement.
他忘记了一些名字.有多大了不起呢?
He did fix the washer.Alright, so he forgot a few names.Big deal.
我自己有时也会发生这种情况.尤其是这个个儿高的孩子,
I do that myself sometimes.Especially the tall kid.What's his name.
他叫什么来着?好的,我会留心吉米的.
Alright, I'll keep an eye on Jimmy.
麦琪:谢谢你,亲爱的.
Maggie: Thank you dear.
杰森:不过,这种经天经日的唠叨得告一段落了.
Jason: But this constant nagging has got to stop.
本:我们又回到了起居室,在这里我们将要见到希佛太太及希佛小姐,
Ben: Here we are, back in the living room, where we are going to see Mrs.
我们将对她会现场抓拍,当然,前提是我们被允许这么做.
Seaver and the seaver girl, caught in the act of being themselves.If it's ok.
麦琪:当然可以,南瓜.
Maggie: Sure pumpkin.
杰妮:南瓜?
Jenny: Pumpkin?
本:我们会把那句剪辑掉的.
Ben: We'll edit that out.
开萝尔:如果拍出来我看着胖,那你不能用.
Carol: If this makes me look fat, you can't use it.
本:还是小心为好,杰妮,不要把她拍进去.
Ben: Play it safe Jenny.Keep her out of the shot.
杰妮:本,我得跟你直说,
Jenny: Ben, I got to be straight with you.
自从今天早上八点起我就一直在这个项目工作,
I've been on this project since eight o clock this morning,
可是,什么事情也没有发生.
and nothing has happened.
本:你想说的到底是什么?
Ben: What are you trying to say?
杰妮:两个词,烦.
Jenny: Two words.Boring.
本:你在说我家人烦么?
Ben: Are you calling my family boring?
杰妮:怎么说呢……
Jenny: Well ...
本:如果你每周把我家放到电视上,
Ben: If you put my family on TV every week,
我保证成千上万的人都会喜欢看的.
I bet millions of people would watch.
杰妮:你说得没错,本,太对了!
Jenny: Yeah Ben.Right!
本:咱们去采访吉米吧.
Ben: Let's go interview Jimmy.
杰妮:我们已经采访过了.
Jenny: We already did.
本:那咱们就再采访一次.他不会记得的.
Ben: Let's go do it again.He won't remember.
麦琪:本,不可以说吉米的闲话.
Maggie: Ben, that is no way to talk about Jimmy.
本:对不起.
Ben: I'm sorry.
麦琪:即使所说的是事实.
Maggie: Even if it is true.
吉米:当然,回到从前,整个这一片空无一物,
Jimmy: Of course, back then,
都是些苹果园,或许是梨园,
this entire neighborhood was nothing but apple orchards.Or was it pears?
不管怎么说都是些水果,因为到了秋天,我就不停地偷水果吃.
Well it was fruit anyway, because in fall I kept stepping on them.
本:后来你是怎么成为修理工的呢?
Ben: How did you become a handy man?
吉米:这样的,从前,我在这个地球上生生死死很多次.
Jimmy: Well, you see, I have lived on this earth many times before.
本:是么?
Ben: Yeah?
吉米:肯定了.每一世呢,我都是个修理工.
Jimmy: You bet ya.And in each life, I was a handy man.
本:真的么?
Ben: Really?
吉米:哦,
Jimmy: Oh, I remember the time when those Chinese fellows asked me to
我还记得中国人要我监理修筑城墙那些日子.
supervise the building of the Great Wall.
本:你是说万里长城?
Ben: You mean the Great Wall?
吉米:对.
Jimmy: Sure, after I got on with it.
本:我不明白.
Ben: I don't get it.
吉米:也许你还太小了点.
Jimmy: Well maybe you are a little too young yet.
本:有部分人认为我年龄太小,任何事也做不了.
Ben: Some people think I'm too young to do anything.
吉米:哦,你知道么,有些人认为我年龄太大,任何事也做不了.
Jimmy: Oh, would you know.Some folks think I'm too old to do anything.
本:那就是说,我们有共同之处.
Ben: So we've got something in common.
吉米:对.遇到那种事情的时候,我简直都要气疯了.你呢?
Jimmy: Yeah.Makes me mad when that happens.How about you?
本:我也是.
Ben: Me too.
吉米:可是,对此你是怎么做的?
Jimmy: But what do you do about it?
本:我大发脾气,喘不上气来,直到我脸色铁青.
Ben: I throw a fit and hold my breath until I turn blue.
吉米:我也一样.
Jimmy: Same here.
开萝尔:最起码窗帘是干净的.
Carol: Well at least the drapes are clean.
麦琪:呃.
Maggie: Uh huh.
开萝尔:妈妈,"希佛家家务的一天",是谁想出来的点子?
Carol: Mum, who came up with the idea of Seaver chore day?
麦琪:你爸爸,你知道的.
Maggie: Your dad.You know that.
开萝尔:您不觉得有趣么,家务一天的创办人本人一件家务也不做.
Carol: Well, don't you find it interesting that the founder of chore day
相反,他还在撰写一篇文章,
is not doing an actual chore?
说他心神不宁,直到家务日才有些起色.
Instead he's writing an article that he put off until chore day.
麦琪:你说的完全正确.所以,
Maggie: You know you're absolutely right.
猜一猜,下个家务日我们会到哪儿去?
So guess where we're going to be next chore day?
开萝尔:哪儿?
Carol: Where?
麦琪:Bloomingdales.
Maggie: Bloomingdales.
吉米:你以前做什么的?
Jimmy: What did you do?
麦琪:杰森!你受伤了?
Maggie: Jason!Are you hurt?
吉米:对此深表遗憾.再也不会发生了.
Jimmy: Sorry about that.Won't happen again.
麦琪:杰森,你给吉米一个机会,这不错,
Maggie: Jason, it was right of you to give Jimmy a chance,
但是,现在还不清楚么?他达不到我们的期望.
but isn't it pretty clear now that he's not up to it?
杰森:好了,首先,我们为什么不能找出来刚才发生了什么?
Jason: Alright, first, why don't we find out what happened?
开萝尔:刚才发生了什么!三个小时,
Carol: What happened!Three hours of boring hard work were ruined.
艰苦,单调的工作前功尽弃.为那个,
Work that we've been doing all day long,
我们已经干了一整天了,而某些人一直躲在写字间里舞笔弄墨.
while some people were ducking out in theory office.Huh!
吉米:有了那件事,迈克,我在这儿呆不住了.你会去看我么?
Jimmy: With that Mikey, I'm out of here.Would you look at me.
迈克:好了,鲍纳,以前,我看到过你去上学的时候,比那个还脏.
Mike: Come on Boner.I've seen you show up to school looking dirtier than that.
开萝尔:迈克,在家务日鲍纳在这儿做什么?
Carol: Mike, what's Boner doing here on chore day?
迈克:开萝尔!和平常一样,这是个非常好的问题,我呢非常高兴你提出这个问题.
Mike: Carol!You know, as usual, that's an excellent question, and I'm very glad you asked.
杰森:现在不行,迈克.我们现在有一个更重要的事情要留意.
Jason: Not now Mike.We've got bigger fish to fry.
鲍纳:如果我可以加入,和你一块儿,那我就留下.
Boner: You know, I'll stay if I can get in on this fish fry with you.
迈克:一言为定,哥们儿.
Mike: Done my friend.
鲍纳:没问题.
Boner: Alright!
开萝尔:爸爸,我不得不赞同妈妈的意见.
Carol: You know dad, I have to agree with mum.Jimmy should go.
得让吉米走.这不是一个友情的问题,这是个能力问题.
This is not a matter of friendship.It's a matter of incompetence.
杰森:我真不敢相信你也开始批评吉米.他是我们的朋友.
Jason: You know I can't believe you're turning on Jimmy too.He's our pal.
除此之外,所有这一类的提法,比如要除掉某人,
And another thing.All this talk about getting rid of a person, a human being,
开掉某人就是因为他能力不足等,会让迈克很不开心的.
just because they're incompetent.That could be very upsetting to mike.
杰森:吉米,我知道你工作的时候一直压力很大,
Jason: Now Jimmy, I know that you're working under a lot of pressure here,
而且你不希望他人的干涉.
and surely don't want to interfere...
麦琪:但是刚才发生的到底是怎么回事?
Maggie: But what the hell happened just now?
杰森:耶!
Jason: Yeah!
吉米:我希望我可以这么说,大夫,
Jimmy: I wish I could say doc.
那是我们修理工们所称的错误.
It was just one of those things that we handy men call a mistake.
麦琪:我也认为那是个错误.
Maggie: That's what I call it.What a coin kee dink.
吉米:我真诚地希望那个错误没有给您造成太大的损失.
Jimmy: I just hope it didn't cause too much mess up there?
麦琪:事实上,吉米……
Maggie: Well as a matter of fact Jimmy..
杰森:我们还是会活得好好的,吉米.亲爱的,是不是?
Jason: We'll live Jimmy.Won't we honey?
麦琪:哦,对,是的.凑和着过吧.
Maggie: Oh yes.Yes.Someonhow.
杰森:我们是不是离解决问题更进一步了,吉米?
Jason: Are we any closer to solving the problem Jimmy?
吉米:可能您的火炉系统里存在一个小的压力泄漏,您会相信么?
Jimmy: Well you may have a small pressure leak in your system.
我的卡车有个压力表,可以量一量.
Would you believe it, I have a gauge in me truck that will tell the tale.
杰森:你都听到他说话了.它是修理工方面的"错误".
Jason: You heard him.It's just what handy men call 'a mistake'.
麦琪:亲爱的,知道么,
Maggie: Honey, you know how when we disagree,
有时候我们意见不一,后来发现我对你错,你总是会为自己辩护.
and then later we find out that I was right, how you always get defensive...
杰森:我不是为自己辩护.我觉得没有丝毫证据可以表明他没有能力做这件事.
Jason: I'm not defensive.
And when you think about it,
I don't think threes one shred of evidence e that he's incompetent.
麦琪:我相信这表明你正在向那方面发展.亲爱的,
Maggie: I believe that exhibit's a heading your way.
迟早,你必要面对有关吉米的事实.
Honey, sooner or later, you are going to face the facts about Jimmy.
杰森:我说的只不过是一个人有权利维护自己的尊严,受到他人的尊重,
Jason: Well I say a man's entitled to keep his dignity until he proves
直到经过实践证明他的能力与这种尊重不相称.
he doesn't deserve it.
麦琪:你固执得很可爱.
Maggie: And I love you for it.
杰森:你要去哪儿?
Jason: Where are you going?
麦琪:哦,我想翻一翻我们的房主保险承包范围.
Maggie: Oh, I just thought I'd browse through our home owner's insurance coverage.
杰森:……
Jason: Et two matey!
迈克:鲍纳,好兄弟,
Mike: Boner my friend.Welcome to the eighties.
欢迎来到80年代.这将给你的生活带过更多的乐趣.
Now this is going to make your life a lot more fun.
鲍纳:我可以把它带回家么?
Boner: Can I take it home with me?
迈克:我们在刷着呢.
Mike: We're painting.
鲍纳:哦.
Boner: Oh.
迈克:鲍纳,我感觉非常难受,
Mike: You know Bone.
尤其是看到你一直在做的这项工作的辛苦程度.不过,
See I feel real bad about the hard work that you've been doing.
我希望看到今天这个房间能被粉刷完成.能行么?现在,
But I would like to get this room painted today.Alright?Now watch me.
看着我.你所需做的一切只不过是把电喷头对准需要喷涂的部分,
All you do is you point the electric sprayer at the area to be covered,
而后,轻轻地扣动扳机……你明白了么?
gently squeeze the trigger...and voila.You got it?
鲍纳:迈克,连傻子都会做这个.
Boner: Mike, even a goon could do this.
迈克:这就是我所想指望的.
Mike: That's what I'm counting on.
鲍纳:很好.
Boner: Nice.
杰森:是什么可以解释幽闭恐怖症大会与会者甚少的原因呢?
Jason: Which explains hwy claustrophobia conventions are so poorly attended.
麦琪:如果你不想跟我争论的话,不要揣度我的心思.
Maggie: If you don't want an argument, don't read my mind.
杰森:与会者很少,与会者很少.麦琪,
Jason: Poorly attended, poorly attended.
你能不能离开我一下,就几分钟而已?请.我今天必须完成这个.
Maggie, could you leave my shades for just a few minutes?Please.
已经到最后一页了.啊,不.
I've got to get this done today, I'm on the very last page.Ah no.
麦琪:什么意思?一切都丢失了么?
Maggie: Does that mean you've lost everything?
杰森:我还不知道,开萝尔是电脑专家.
Jason: I don't know yet.Carols the computer expert.
开萝尔:全家都没电.
Carol: Power is out all over the house.
杰森:那意味着我的二十页已经全部丢失,是么?
Jason: Does that mean I've lost all twenty eight pages.
开萝尔:不.
Carol: No.
杰森:哦,太好了.
Jason: Oh good.
开萝尔:在你写的时候,你已经在保存完成了的页.是吧?
Carol: You were saving the pages as you went along.Right?
杰森:保存页?
Jason: Saving pages?
吉米:希望没有惊吓到任何人.我会马上恢复供电的.
Jimmy: Hope that didn't take anyone out there by surprise?
对不起.
I'll get power back in a sec.I'm sorry.
杰森:是那个么,吉米?
Jason: Was that Jimmy?
麦琪:它不是雪莉*麦可伦.
Maggie: It wasn't Shirley McLain.
鲍纳:迈克,我只知道我听到了一个声音,
Boner: Mikey.All I know is that I heard a voice say 'I'm sorry' and it
它在说"对不起",听起来像是上帝的声音.
sounded like god.
迈克:不不,吉米!
Mike: No no.Jimmy!
鲍纳:你叫他吉米?
Boner: You call him Jimmy?
迈克:你对这件事都做了什么?
Mike: What did you do to this thing?
鲍纳:我不知道,也许鼻子堵住了.
Boner: I don't know.Maybe the nozzle was clogged.
迈克:肯定没堵住.
Mike: It's definitely not clogged.
本:爸爸,电视刚才没电了,不过现在又来电了.
Ben: Dad the TV went off, but its back on now.
杰森:我们知道了,本.
Jason: We know Ben.
本:还有啊,跟我无关.
Ben: And I had nothing to do with it.
麦琪:我们知道了,本.
Maggie: We know Ben.
杰森:如果要你去告诉家庭某成员离开你会怎么做?
Jason: Well how do you go and tell a member of the family to get out?
本:我告诉你了,那不是我的错.
Ben: I told you it wasn't my fault.
杰森:他们知道了,本.
Jason: They know Ben.
麦琪:亲爱的,如果这么做你受不了,那就让我来.
Maggie: Honey if you can't bear to do this then I will.
开萝尔:我有主意了.我们把房子卖了,然后搬走.
Carol: I've got it.We'll sell the house and move.
杰森:真有那么简单就好了.
Jason: I wish it were that simple.
迈克:好了.我想知道结果,并且我现在就要.
Mike: Alright.I want some answers and I want them now.
鲍纳:叫吉米的那个,他在这儿做什么呢?
Boner: Yeah.What in the name of Jimmy is going on around here?
哦,原谅我的语言.
Oh, excuse my language.
开萝尔:你们俩怎么了?
Carol: What happened to you guys?
迈克:现在,我要向这儿的人提问.这个家,现在发生了什么事?
Mike: Now I'll ask the questions around here.Now what is going on in this house?
杰森:我正在努力寻找一个让一位和蔼可亲的老人柔肠寸断的方法.
Jason: Well I'm trying to find a way to break a dear old mans heart.
这就是所发生的.
That's what.
麦琪:我知道这会伤害你,我知道这会伤你有多深.
Maggie: I know how much this hurts you dad.
开萝尔:他是唯一的一位还相信吉米的人.
Carol: Well he was the only one how kept believing in Jimmy.
鲍纳:哦,我也还相信吉米.
Boner: Oh I still believe in Jimmy.
开萝尔:鲍纳,请别闹了!
Carol: Boner please!
鲍纳:什么什么什么?是从什么时候起,你们都变成了无神论都?
Boner: What what what?Since when did all of you turn into atheists.hu?
杰森:嗨,吉米,我们得谈一谈.
Jason: Hey Jimmy, we've got to talk now.Se...
吉米:嗨,大夫.这还能等么?我确实需要集中精力.
Jimmy: Hey doc.If it can wait, I really have to concentrate here.
杰森:不,不能拖了,吉米.我觉得不能再拖了.
Jason: Sure.No, it can't Jimmy.I don't think so.
吉米:好吧.怎么回事?
Jimmy: Ok.What's up?
杰森:吉米,好了.你是个体育迷么,是么?
Jason: Jimmy, come on.You're a sports fan right?
吉米:对.
Jimmy: Sure.
杰森:咱们谈一谈穆罕默德*阿里.
Jason: Let's talk about Mohammed Ali.
吉米:哦.他是最伟大的.
Jimmy: Oh.Cassius Clay.He was the greatest.
杰森:对.不过,什么时候所有人都认为他应该收手不干了,还记得么?
Jason: Yeah.But remember when everyone thought that he should hang it up.
吉米:但是,他没听.
Jimmy: But, he didn't listen.
杰森:一点儿没错.
Jason: Exactly.
吉米:于是,
Jimmy: So he became the only man to win the heavy weight championship
他成了唯一一位三次赢得世界重量级冠军的人.
of the world...three times.
杰森:我是在谈后来发生的事情.
Jason: Well I was talking about later.
吉米:人们抛弃了他,人们本来可以更好的了解.
Jimmy: Oh sure.People gave up on the man.People who should have known better.
本:穆罕默德*阿里在这儿不是一个恰当的例子.
Jason: Well Mohammed Ali is a bad example here.
吉米:想说明什么的例子?
Jimmy: Of what?
杰森:我不知道,给我一分钟,让我想一想.
Jason: I don't know.Give me a minute, I'll think of it.
吉米:思考的线索丢了,是么?常有的事儿,尤其是年龄越来越大的时候.
Jimmy: Losing your train of thought , hey?Well it happens.As you get older.
麦琪:可怜的杰森,可怜的吉米.
Maggie: Poor Jason.Poor Jimmy.
迈克:鲍纳,不用担心.我做完这些的时候,它不但会很新,而且会很好.55,哪儿可以清洗一下鲍纳的衣服?
Mike: Boner don't worry.When I'm done with these, it'll be as good as new
Mum where can I clean Boners clothes
麦琪:我不关心.
Maggie: I don't care.
开萝尔:鲍纳,你可以穿我的浴衣.
Carol: Boner, you're wearing my bathrobe.
鲍纳:哦,没事的.
Boner: Oh, I don't mind.
迈克:我们能把这些扔到洗衣机里么?
Mike: Yeah, um, can we fit these in the washer?
开萝尔:你得等,所有的地毯都在里面呢.
Carol: Well you'll have to wait.All the rugs are in there.
鲍纳:我想去逮些鱼.
Boner: I think I'll go get some of that fish.
麦琪:等等,开萝尔,你刚才是不是说你把所有的地毯一次全都放到洗衣机里了?
Maggie: Wait a minute Carol.Did you just say that you put all the rugs in the washer at once?
开萝尔:对.有什么问题么?
Carol: Well yes.Is that a problem?
麦琪:有.洗衣机会超负荷,会发出可怕的噪音,跳动,最后断电.
Maggie: Yes.The washer would overload and make horrible noises, and jump around and shut off.
开萝尔:对不起.
Carol: Sorry.
麦琪:也许这不是他的错.
Maggie: Maybe it wasn't his fault.
开萝尔:谁的错?
Carol: Whose fault?
麦琪:所有这些烟灰怎么办?
Maggie: Well what about all the soot?
本的录相:我会大发脾气,喘不过气来,直到我变得脸色青紫.
Ben's video: I throw a fit and hold my breath until I turn blue.
杰森:嗨,看我的摄像作品.
Jason: Hey, look at my camera work!
本的录相:吉米:我得回去工作了.
Ben's video: Jimmy: I got to get back to work.
本的录相:本:我能帮些什么么?
Ben's video Ben: Can I help?
本的录相:吉米:哦,可以.拿着这个胶管,
Bens video: Jimmy: Oh sure, sure.Take this hose and hook it to the vacuum.
把它固定在真空吸尘器上.确实,档位在"吸入"上.
Be sure you're on the intake.
本:哦,不!
Ben: Oh no!
本的录相:吉米:不不,另外一个.
Bens video: Jimmy: No no, the other one.
本:我不知道你把这段儿也录了.
Ben: I didn't know you taped this part.
杰森:嗨,我的录相机从来不停.
Jason: Hey my camera never stops.
麦琪:本,让它放.
Maggie: Ben, let it play.
迈克:鲍纳,你必须相信我,
Mike: Look Boner.You're just going to have to trust me.
这儿没鱼,什么鱼都没有.
There is no fish here, whatsoever.
本的录相:本:对不起.
Ben's video: Ben I'm sorry
本的录相:吉米:没关系,本.我会补偿你的.真对不起,以后再也不会发生了.
Ben's video: Jimmy: That's alright Bennie, I'll cover for you.Sorry about that.Won't happen again.
本的录相:本:谢谢你吉米.
Ben's video: Ben: Thanks Jimmy.
麦琪:就是说,不是吉米,而是你?
Maggie: So it wasn't Jimmy, it was you?
本:现在我想回自己的房间了.
Ben: Well, I'm going to go to my room now.
麦琪:坐下,本.
Maggie: Sit down Ben.
开萝尔:那还不能解释为什么电会没有.
Carol: You know, that still doesn't explain the power going off.
麦琪:对,吉米来这儿,修的是气炉,而不是电气.
Maggie: Yeah, Jimmy was here to fix a gas furnace, not the electricity.
鲍纳:或许我不该在这儿这么说话,不过,
Boner: Um, I might be out of line here,
如果存在气体泄漏的话,
but in the case of a gas leak,
第一件事就是切断电源,然后进行检查.
the first thing you do is shut of the power to check on it.
麦琪:哦,哦,杰森!杰森,等等.
Maggie: Oh.Oh Jason!Jason wait.
鲍纳:如果只有一件我了解的事情的话,那就是燃气.
Boner: If there's one thing I know about, its gas.
麦琪:谢谢你,吉米,上帝保佑你.
Maggie: Thank you Jimmy and god bless you.
杰森:对,吉米.你一定要过来吃晚饭.
Jason: Yeah Jimmy.You have to come over to dinner.
麦琪:或者午饭.
Maggie: Or lunch.
迈克:对,这周哪天都行.
Mike: Mike: Yeah, any day this week.
麦琪:本周的任何一天.
Maggie: Every day this week.
杰森:为什么你不进来呢?
Jason: Why don't you just move in?
开萝尔:我们爱你,吉米.
Carol: We love you Jimmy.
麦琪:我想现在就进去,弄坏点东西.你会修么?
Maggie: I want to go inside right now and break something.Would you fix it?
吉米:哦,没问题,没问题.你只要给我打个电话就行.
Jimmy: Oh sure, sure.You only have to call me.
麦琪:好的.
Maggie: Ok.
所有人:再见,吉米.
Everyone: Bye Jimmy
杰森:再见.
Jason: See you.
本:好了,卡特尔太太,
Ben: Well Mrs.Cutter, That's a day in the life of the Seavers,
这就是希佛一家的一天.我希望您过得愉快,
and I hope you had fun, cos I know I sure did.
因为我的的确确是过得非常愉快.我以前学习过,
And I learned things too, which you're supposed to do when you do school junk.
都是做学校功课时应该做的那些.但是我在今天所学的就是,
But what I leaned today is, you should let old people do stuff,
应该放手让老人去做事,因为他们懂得很多.
cos they know a whole lot.
正如我爸爸所说过的:我们没有抛弃吉米,这是件好事,因为我们会失去一个称职的修理工,
Like my dad said: it's a good thing we didn't give up on Jimmy,
并失去一个好朋友.好了,
cos we would have lost a good handy man, and a good friend.
这是本和杰妮制作完成的.本录相其实还会好许多,
well, that's it for me and Jenny.
但是不要忘记,我还只是一个孩子.
This video could have been a whole lot better, but remember, I'm just a kid.
再见,卡特尔太太.
Bye Mrs.Cutter.
杰妮:再见,卡特尔太太.
Jenny: Bye Mrs.Cutter.
杰森:迈克!
Jason: Mike!
迈克:来了,我马上就完事,爸爸.
杰森:嗨,迈克,晚饭时间到了.
00:22:55,000
Mike: Yeah, I'll be through in one second dad. Jason: Hey Mike.Dinner.